<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="demo.xsl"?>
<SHAKESPEARE_SCENE>

	<SPEECH>
		<SPEAKER>ROMEO</SPEAKER>
		<DIALOGUE>
			<LINE>He jests at scars that never felt a wound.</LINE>
			<STAGEDIR>JULIET appears above at a window</STAGEDIR>
			<LINE>But, soft! what light through yonder window breaks?</LINE>
			<LINE>It is the east, and Juliet is the sun.</LINE>
			<LINE>Arise, fair sun, and kill the envious moon,</LINE>
			<LINE>Who is already sick and pale with grief,</LINE>
			<LINE>That thou her maid art far more fair than she:</LINE>
			<LINE>Be not her maid, since she is envious;</LINE>
			<LINE>Her vestal livery is but sick and green</LINE>
			<LINE>And none but fools do wear it; cast it off.</LINE>
			<LINE>It is my lady, O, it is my love!</LINE>
			<LINE>O, that she knew she were!</LINE>
			<LINE>She speaks yet she says nothing: what of that?</LINE>
			<LINE>Her eye discourses; I will answer it.</LINE>
			<LINE>I am too bold, 'tis not to me she speaks:</LINE>
			<LINE>Two of the fairest stars in all the heaven,</LINE>
			<LINE>Having some business, do entreat her <MADLIB>eyes</MADLIB></LINE>
			<LINE>To twinkle in their spheres till they return.</LINE>
			<LINE>What if her eyes were there, they in her head?</LINE>
			<LINE>The brightness of her cheek would shame those stars,</LINE>
			<LINE>As daylight doth a lamp; her eyes in heaven</LINE>
			<LINE>Would through the airy region stream so bright</LINE>
			<LINE>That birds would sing and think it were not night.</LINE>
			<LINE>See, how she leans her cheek upon her hand!</LINE>
			<LINE>O, that I were a glove upon that hand,</LINE>
			<LINE>That I might touch that cheek!</LINE>
		</DIALOGUE>
	</SPEECH>

	<SPEECH>
		<SPEAKER>JULIET</SPEAKER>
		<DIALOGUE>
			<LINE>Ay me!</LINE>
		</DIALOGUE>
	</SPEECH>

	<SPEECH>
		<SPEAKER>ROMEO</SPEAKER>
		<DIALOGUE>
			<LINE>She speaks:</LINE>
			<LINE>O, speak again, bright angel! for thou art</LINE>
			<LINE>As glorious to this night, being o'er my head</LINE>
			<LINE>As is a winged messenger of heaven</LINE>
			<LINE>Unto the white-upturned wondering eyes</LINE>
			<LINE>Of mortals that fall back to gaze on him</LINE>
			<LINE>When he bestrides the lazy-pacing clouds</LINE>
			<LINE>And sails upon the bosom of the air.</LINE>
		</DIALOGUE>
	</SPEECH>

	<SPEECH>
		<SPEAKER>JULIET</SPEAKER>
		<DIALOGUE>
			<LINE>O Romeo, Romeo! wherefore art thou Romeo?</LINE>
			<LINE>Deny thy father and refuse thy name;</LINE>
			<LINE>Or, if thou wilt not, be but sworn my love,</LINE>
			<LINE>And I'll no longer be a Capulet.</LINE>
		</DIALOGUE>
	</SPEECH>

	<SPEECH>
		<SPEAKER>ROMEO</SPEAKER>
		<DIALOGUE>
			<LINE>Shall I hear more, or shall I speak at this?</LINE>
		</DIALOGUE>
	</SPEECH>

	<SPEECH>
		<SPEAKER>JULIET</SPEAKER>
		<DIALOGUE>
			<LINE>'Tis but thy name that is my enemy;</LINE>
			<LINE>Thou art thyself, though not a Montague.</LINE>
			<LINE>What's Montague? it is nor hand, nor foot,</LINE>
			<LINE>Nor arm, nor face, nor any other part</LINE>
			<LINE>Belonging to a man. O, be some other name!</LINE>
			<LINE>What's in a name? that which we call a rose</LINE>
			<LINE>By any other name would smell as sweet;</LINE>
			<LINE>So Romeo would, were he not Romeo call'd,</LINE>
			<LINE>Retain that dear perfection which he owes</LINE>
			<LINE>Without that title. Romeo, doff thy name,</LINE>
			<LINE>And for that name which is no part of thee</LINE>
			<LINE>Take all myself.</LINE>
		</DIALOGUE>
	</SPEECH>

	<SPEECH>
		<SPEAKER>ROMEO</SPEAKER>
		<DIALOGUE>
			<LINE>I take thee at thy word:</LINE>
			<LINE>Call me but love, and I'll be new baptized;</LINE>
			<LINE>Henceforth I never will be Romeo.</LINE>
		</DIALOGUE>
	</SPEECH>

	<SPEECH>
		<SPEAKER>JULIET</SPEAKER>
		<DIALOGUE>
			<LINE>What man art thou that thus bescreen'd in night</LINE>
			<LINE>So stumblest on my counsel?</LINE>
		</DIALOGUE>
	</SPEECH>

	<SPEECH>
		<SPEAKER>ROMEO</SPEAKER>
		<DIALOGUE>
			<LINE>By a name</LINE>
			<LINE>I know not how to tell thee who I am:</LINE>
			<LINE>My name, dear saint, is hateful to myself,</LINE>
			<LINE>Because it is an enemy to thee;</LINE>
			<LINE>Had I it written, I would tear the word.</LINE>
		</DIALOGUE>
	</SPEECH>

	<SPEECH>
		<SPEAKER>JULIET</SPEAKER>
		<DIALOGUE>
			<LINE>My ears have not yet drunk a hundred words</LINE>
			<LINE>Of that tongue's utterance, yet I know the sound:</LINE>
			<LINE>Art thou not Romeo and a Montague?</LINE>
		</DIALOGUE>
	</SPEECH>

	<SPEECH>
		<SPEAKER>ROMEO</SPEAKER>
		<DIALOGUE>
			<LINE>Neither, fair saint, if either thee dislike.</LINE>
		</DIALOGUE>
	</SPEECH>

	<SPEECH>
		<SPEAKER>JULIET</SPEAKER>
		<DIALOGUE>
			<LINE>How camest thou hither, tell me, and wherefore?</LINE>
			<LINE>The orchard walls are high and hard to climb,</LINE>
			<LINE>And the place death, considering who thou art,</LINE>
			<LINE>If any of my kinsmen find thee here.</LINE>
		</DIALOGUE>
	</SPEECH>

	<SPEECH>
		<SPEAKER>ROMEO</SPEAKER>
		<DIALOGUE>
			<LINE>With love's light wings did I o'er-perch these walls;</LINE>
			<LINE>For stony limits cannot hold love out,</LINE>
			<LINE>And what love can do that dares love attempt;</LINE>
			<LINE>Therefore thy kinsmen are no let to me.</LINE>
		</DIALOGUE>
	</SPEECH>

	<SPEECH>
		<SPEAKER>JULIET</SPEAKER>
		<DIALOGUE>
			<LINE>If they do see thee, they will murder thee.</LINE>
		</DIALOGUE>
	</SPEECH>

	<SPEECH>
		<SPEAKER>ROMEO</SPEAKER>
		<DIALOGUE>
			<LINE>Alack, there lies more peril in thine eye</LINE>
			<LINE>Than twenty of their swords: look thou but sweet,</LINE>
			<LINE>And I am proof against their enmity.</LINE>
		</DIALOGUE>
	</SPEECH>

</SHAKESPEARE_SCENE>